WELCOME
（欢迎光临）
Well, this is amazing!
这太令人惊讶了
It might be the first time a human has made it this far.
这可能是第一次 有人类能够走到这一步
In at least 1,000 years.
至少近一千年来
A human?
人类？
Not a human… Shit.
不是人类 该死
Oh dear.
天啊
Don't run.
不要跑
I'm not planning to kill you…
我没打算杀你
Yet.
还没有
He's so strong…
他太强大了
How did he--?
他是怎么做到的？
I know why she ran.
我知道她为什么跑
Compared to the other monsters, he's clearly…
跟其他怪物相比 他显然
much stronger.
更强大
Let go of her.
放开她
Sagirin…
佐切
Don't glower at me that like.
不要那样怒视我
I just want to have a little chat with you.
我只是想和你聊一聊
What are you?
你是什么？
It's Lord Tensen.
天仙大人
This person is…
这个人是
The Peony Sprite… Enthroned Amoghavajra.
牡丹 不空就君
He is… Lord Tensen…
他是天仙大人
Hoko… You're alive?
树人 你还活着？
That won't kill him.
那不会杀死他
It'll only speed up Arborification. Once he's fully a tree, he's done.
只会加速他的树化 一旦他完全变成一棵树 他就完蛋了
No!
不
It is regrettable, but it is the will of the gods…
虽然遗憾 但这是神的旨意
I can only pray that my soul
我只能祈祷我的灵魂
will be invited to Horai.
能被邀请到蓬莱
Just so you know,
告诉你吧
all that about Amoghavajra and souls and stuff…
关于不空就君和灵魂之类的
It's all fake.
全都是假的
What?
什么？
Or maybe more of an expedient.
或者说是个权宜之计
We had to create order on the island, so we made a religion.
我们必须在岛上建立秩序 所以我们创立了一个宗教
This island is an experiment on life.
这个岛是一个有关生命的实验
You and everything else on this island
你们和这个岛上的一切
were simply test subjects born from experiments.
只是实验中诞生的试验对象
That can't be…
那不可能…
And the humans who come to this island are all,
而来到这个岛上的人类
in the end, materials for research.
最终都成为了研究的素材
These are Kiyoshi.
这些是狂士
I made them from humans.
我用人类制作了它们
They're made from… humans?
它们是由人类制成的？
Yep. They were originally humans who came to the island.
是的 它们最初 是来到这个岛上的人类
I just love to tinker around and figure out how I can play with each one.
我只是喜欢折腾 想知道如何玩弄每一个人
It's kind of funny, isn't it?
挺有趣的 不是吗？
But this wasn't the original plan for the humans.
但这并不是对人类最初的计划
Good quality humans become Tan.
优质的人类会变成棕褐色
Tan…
棕褐色
That's the elixir, right?
就是长生不老药？
The elixir?
长生不老药？
All the humans who've come here have talked about the same thing.
所有来过这里的人类 都在谈论同样的事情
The elixir of life…
长生不死药
The fountain of youth… Ambrosia, food of the gods…
青春之泉 众神的神食
I'm sorry to say we don't have anything like that here.
很抱歉告诉你 我们这里没有这样的东西
Tan may be indispensable to us,
对我们来说 棕褐色可能是必不可少的
but any human who drinks it will simply Arborify.
但人类喝下去只会树化
The Hoko and the flower people are almost immortal,
树人和花人几乎是不朽的
but not eternally young.
但并非永远年轻
My colleagues are looking into that,
我的同事正在研究这个问题
but the solution will take a while.
但解决方案需要一些时间
Either way,
不管怎样
we don't have what you're looking for on this island.
我们这个岛上没有你们在找的东西
There's no… elixir?
没有不死药？
So, what's going to happen to him?
那他怎么办？
Without the elixir he won't get a pardon…
没有不死药 他就得不到赦免
So, it's the end of the road for you all.
所以你们的命运就到头了
Why don't you just be good and come with me?
为什么不乖乖跟我走呢？
There's a lot of things I want to try with you…
我想和你尝试很多事情
Ninja Art: Body Replacement.
忍术：身体替代术
That's enough to kill any kind of monster.
这足以杀死任何一种怪物
Just the henchmen left.
只剩下跟班了
But why are they spacing out like that?
但他们为什么那样发呆？
Might as well run now!
最好还是先逃跑
Sagirin!
佐切
Uh… Right.
好
Thanks for your help earlier.
刚才谢谢你的帮忙
Even though I ran away.
虽然我逃跑了
Were you shocked about the elixir?
你是被不死药的事震惊了吗？
I totally get it!
我完全理解
But you know…
但你知道
The priority is staying alive.
现在最重要的是活下来
As long as we're alive, we can manage everything else.
只要我们活着 就可以应付一切
Let's focus on doing that.
把注意力集中在那里吧
Change your mindset. Now, we run!
改变你的思维方式 现在我们逃跑
Right!
好
-Senta, hurry up! -Ah, okay!
-仙汰 快点 -好
I like you. You have talent.
我喜欢你 你有天赋
But you're not quite right.
但你弄错了
The Kiyoshi aren't my henchmen.
狂士并不是我的跟班
They're my toys.
它们是我的玩具
See, that was funny, right?
看 很好玩吧？
You dodged it. You must have good eyes.
你躲过了 你一定有好眼力
Or rather… Can you actually see Tao?
还是说你真的能看到道？
It's the first time I've ever heard the word "Tao."
我第一次听到“道”这个词
At my old haunt, they used to call it "Qi."
在我原来的地方 他们称之为“气”
But it looks like you can't use it yet.
但看起来你还无法使用它
I suppose I might as well teach you--
我不妨教教你
Please wait!
请等一下！
If it has to do with her life or death,
如果涉及到她的生死
it must go through me.
必须经过我的同意
I have a job to do too…
我也有我的任务
TAMESHI ITTORYO FIFTH RANK YAMADA ASAEMON SENTA
（试剑一刀流五段 山田浅右卫门仙汰）
The other two looked like they have potential.
另外两个人看起来也有潜力
If yours is the same, that's fine.
如果你也一样 那很好
Ninja girl,
忍者女孩
I'm going to teach you how to use Tao.
我要教你如何使用道
If you're talented enough, we could do Bochu Justu…
如果你足够有天赋 我们可以一起练房中术
or you'll become a high-quality Tan.
或者你会成为优质的棕褐色
Looks like you're his favorite.
看来你是他的最爱
-Right? -Shut up.
-是吧？ -闭嘴
To think that Senta would be so quick to draw…
仙汰竟然如此迅速地出手
And for a criminal, no less…
而且还是为了一个罪犯
I wonder…
我在想
If he has some special feelings for her…
他是不是对她有特殊的感情
I don't care about anyone but the ninja girl.
我只在乎忍者女孩一个人
So get out of my way.
所以别挡我的路
Sagirin!
佐切！
Forget about her.
别管她了
What I just did was Toate.
我刚才用的是刀手术
It's a technique where you collect Tao and throw it,
这是一种收集道并投掷的技术
but humans can't learn it,
但人类无法学会它
so just forget about it.
所以还是算了吧
I'd rather you just start with the bas--
我倒是希望你能先从基础开始
Oh?
哦？
Don't interfere, fatty.
别多管闲事 胖子
I believe I told you to speak through me.
我想我告诉过你经过我同意
-Besides… -He's right, Senta. You are interfering!
-而且… -他说得对 别多管闲事
Since he just won't die,
既然他就是不死之身
he can test me all he wants.
他可以随便对我进行试验
Ninja Art: Sticky String!
忍术：粘丝
I metabolized a potion within my body and secreted it out.
在体内形成毒液并分泌出来
It's my own personal ninja art.
这是我个人的忍者之术
That's an acidic snake poison.
这是一种酸性蛇毒
Ninja Art: Honey Prison.
忍术：蜜之牢
And then… Ninja Art: Line Cutting!
然后 忍术：断线
You know, you just made use of Tao.
你知道吗？你刚才使用了道
No ordinary human could metabolize poisonous liquids.
普通人类无法代谢有毒液体
But your use of Tao is ambiguous.
但你对道的运用还不明确
You need to polish your technique.
你需要提高技巧
If we don't let his eyes grow back we might have a chance!
如果我们不让他的眼睛长回来 我们可能有机会
Oh, I see.
我明白了
Okay.
好吧
Let's try it like this for a bit.
我们试一会儿这种方法吧
Senta, get out of the way!
仙汰 让开！
You get out of the way!
你走开
Tao is a sensation…
道是一种感觉
You wear it like clothing,
你像穿衣服一样穿戴它
and then feel it in everything around you.
然后在周围的一切中感受到它
If you can't use it, then it's out of reach for humanity after all.
如果你无法使用它 那么 对于人类来说 它就是遥不可及的
You'd be no match for us.
你不是我们的对手
Now, then…
那么
Welcome to Horai.
欢迎来到蓬莱
How do we face a monster like this?
我们要如何对付这样的怪物？
Hoko, is there anything…
树人 有没有什么…
Does Lord Tensen have any weaknesses?
天仙大人有什么弱点吗？
He is a god.
他是神明
If this is divine punishment, then I will accept it.
如果这是神罚 那我将接受它
I sympathize from the bottom of my heart.
我从心底里同情你
But at this rate, we will all die,
但以这样的进展 我们都会死
and you will never see Mei again!
你将永远见不到梅了！
Any clue at all would do…
任何线索都可以
Your Body Replacement thing…
你那个身体替代的技能
You used Tao for that too.
也用到了道
And it has the same properties as mine.
而且它的性质和我的一样
Interesting!
真有趣
I didn't know you could get close to Hojutsu with self-study.
我不知道你可以通过自学接近法术
Well, I think it's time to kill the fat guy.
好了 我想是时候杀掉那个胖子了
You recovered fast.
你恢复得很快
But there's nothing you can do.
但你无能为力
You only have average amounts of Tao.
你只有普通的道量
Read your opponent's intentions through their movements!
通过对手的动作读懂他的意图！
Yes! However, if there's no intent to his movement…
是！但如果他的动作中 没有意图的话…
Cut him down from his Tanden!
就从他的丹田处砍他
According to legend…
根据传说
Tao is born from the Tanden,
道从丹田诞生
flows over the whole body, and returns to the Tanden.
流过全身 然后返回丹田
If you eradicate it, surely…
如果你除掉它 肯定…
Close, but I'm telling you, you can't do it.
很接近了 但我告诉你 你做不到
First of all, you don't have enough Tao,
首先 你没有足够的道
so I'll just regenerate any wounds you give me.
所以 你给我的伤口 我再生就好了
No human, certainly not any here,
没有人类 尤其是这里的人
even the ninja girl, can handle enough Tao to kill me.
即使是忍者女孩 都无法使用足够的道杀死我
Now that I've seen it up close, I've got it.
现在我近距离看到了 我明白了
I believe it's the same.
我相信它是一样的
I knew it! I can read his movements!
我就知道 我能读懂他的动作
What was that?
刚才那是什么？
The amount of Tao is controlled by the mind…
道的量由心控制
But she can manifest it in an instant?
但她能瞬间让其显现？
But that's not what's important.
但这不重要
Could this woman… possibly…?
难道这个女人…
Yuzuriha!
杠
I know. That wound…
我知道 那个伤口
It's not regenerating.
没有再生
When I got close to him,
当我靠近他时
I felt a special aura.
我感受到一种特殊的气息
If that's Tao…
如果那就是道
I know how to kill him.
我知道如何杀死他了
I've felt the same aura from Gabimaru…
我曾从画眉丸身上感受到同样的气息
And at other times…
还有其他时候
From Rokurota, the Giant of Bizen…
从备前的大巨人 陆郎太身上
Were they using Tao?
他们在使用道吗？
It's just a hypothesis, but…
这只是一种假设 但是…
In order to wound him,
为了伤到他
you'd need more than a normal amount of Tao.
你需要超过正常量的道
And Sagirin can temporarily increase her Tao through breath control…
佐切可以通过调息临时增加她的道量
But that's not all.
但这不是全部
The reason why Tensen can't regenerate…
天仙为什么无法再生？
Leave this to me!
把这交给我
That's an unusual kind of Tao…
这是一种不同寻常的道
And it's poisonous to me?
而且对我有毒？
That's awesome!
太棒了
What will I make out of you?
我能从你身上得到什么？
Or… will you kill me?
或者你会杀了我吗？
Wait, Sagiri!
等等 佐切
He's strong.
他很强大
The three of us should work together.
我们三人必须合作
Hojutsu: Earth Yin…
法术：地阴
Night Pilgrim.
夜行者
He's gone--!
他不见了
He's not gone!
他没有消失
He's just made his Tao so faint we can't sense him!
他只是将他的道变得微弱 使得我们无法感知到他
It's the same trick as Body Replacement!
这和身体替代是一样的伎俩
Do it now!
现在动手！
Calm the heart… Stillness and Movement… Coexisting…
心静 动静 并存
Kiyoshi! Kill the ninja woman!
狂士 杀了那个忍者女人
Thanks, Senta!
谢谢 仙汰
We're a team, right?
我们是个团队 对吧？
Oopsie-daisy!
哎呀
Teamwork! Thanks, Senta!
团队合作 谢谢 仙汰
Sure…
不客气
Oops.
哎呀
I can read your movement.
我能读懂你的动作
Plus, you're easy to dodge between breaths.
而且你的呼吸很容易躲过
My breathing… I'm exhausted!
我的呼吸…我已经精疲力竭
I can't keep this up…
我无法再坚持下去
Nice teamwork.
合作得很好
Now's my chance…
现在是我的机会
Naive.
天真
He's… Flying?
他…他飞起来了？
Hojutsu: Earth Yang - Sky Pilgrim.
法术：地阳 天行者
By interfering with the Tao in the atmosphere,
通过干扰大气中的道
I can create footholds in the air.
我可以在空中创造立足点
Well, naturally,
当然
if you don't know how it works…
如果你不知道它的原理
I might look no different from a god.
我可能看起来和神明没什么区别
Here's another way to use Tao.
这是道的另一种使用方法
Senjutsu: Tin Splinter.
仙术：锡碎片
How am I supposed to fight this?!
我怎么可能应付这个？
Senta!
仙汰！
My vision's getting hazy…
我的视野变得模糊
That breathing pattern is stealing more than my physical strength.
那种呼吸模式不仅仅偷取了我的体力
I don't know how much more I can take…
我不知道我还能坚持多久
It's too early to quit, Sagirin!
现在放弃还为时过早
This all shows
这一切都表明
that she's hiding her panic.
她在隐藏她的恐慌
She always dodges your attacks.
她总是躲过你的攻击
I think there's some kind of compatibility with Tao,
我觉得她可能与道有某种相容性
and yours might be a weakness for her.
而你的道对她来说可能是一个弱点
But… That monster…
但是 那个怪物…
Exactly! She's a monster. She's not a god.
没错 她是个怪物 她不是神明
So… we can kill her!
所以我们可以杀了她
I'll restrain her, so you cut her down!
我控制住她 你来砍她
You're quite… positive.
你真是积极啊
Of course I am.
当然
Since I don't plan on dying today.
因为我不打算今天就死
Not one bit!
一点都不！
It's useless.
没用的
Yuzuriha!
杠！
Can't you dodge them?
你躲不开吗？
You'll die, you know.
你会死的 知道吗？
Come down, fake god!
下来吧 假神明！
I'll kill anyone who…
我会杀掉任何
messes with my life!
冒犯我生活的人！
I'd even a kill a real god!
即使是真正的神明！
Sagirin, now!
佐切 就是现在！
Okay!
好！
That woman…
那个女人
is so irritating.
真是让人讨厌
Nice work, Yuzuriha.
干得好 杠
Now he shouldn't be able to move, regeneration or not.
现在他应该无法移动 无论再生与否
Don't tell me you plan to die with me?
难道你打算和我一起死吗？
Hang him by a thread, Sagiri!
用绳子吊起他 佐切！
I'm on it!
我来！
Looks like… he's not moving.
他看起来不动了
Seems we were right about his weak spot.
看来我们对他的弱点的判断是正确的
That was a gamble.
那真是赌博
We did it, you and me.
我们做到了 你和我
What about me…?
那我呢？
Hoko…
树人
How are you?
你还好吗？
I'm not… a tree yet…
我还没变成树
I'm glad.
太好了
I don't want to think about
我不想去想象
how there's six other monsters like this.
还有另外六个像这样的怪物
What mysterious black magic Tao is.
道是什么神秘的黑魔法？
He was even stronger than Hoko said… surpassing human intelligence.
他甚至比树人说的更强大 超越了人类智慧
What is this strange fatigue?
这是种什么奇怪的疲劳的感觉？
Did we really take down a Lord Tensen that easily?
我们真的轻易击败了一个天仙吗？
More importantly…
更重要的是
The fact that the elixir doesn't exist is also a problem…
不死药根本不存在也是一个问题
What do we do now?
现在我们该怎么办？
We have to do something.
我们必须采取行动
If it doesn't exist, it doesn't exist. Let's think of another plan.
如果它不存在那就不存在吧 我们得想出另一个计划
Aww, my skin is all dry.
我的皮肤都干了
But look… There are all made of gold!
但是瞧 这些都是金子做的
Do you think we could bring all this back instead?
你觉得我们能把这些东西带回去吗？
Let's… rest a moment.
让我们稍作休息吧
Alright…
好
Yuzuriha's utterly indefatigable.
杠真是无法赶到疲倦啊
Senta, you have feelings for her, don't you?
仙汰 你对她有感觉吧？
Ah, no… Not…
不 不是的
Umm…
那个…
Well, I… can't help but feel jealous of her sense of freedom.
其实我不禁嫉妒她的自由感
That is something well beyond my ability.
那是我无法企及的东西
What do you mean?
这是什么意思？
When I was little, I wanted to be a painter.
小时候 我想成为一名画家
But… the men in every generation of my family
但根据传统
traditionally become students of the Yamada Clan.
我家每一代男性 都会成为山田家的学生
I could not break that tradition.
我不能打破这个传统
In truth, I hated…
事实上 我讨厌
being a Yamada, and being an executioner.
成为一个山田人 成为一个处刑者
I despised killing people.
我憎恶杀人
For a long time, I tried to justify the murders.
长久以来 我试图为这些谋杀开脱
That's why I know so much about religions, from my search for answers.
这就是为什么我对宗教了解很多 因为我在寻找答案
The irony is that they deemed me hardworking,
讽刺的是 他们认为我勤奋
and my rank kept going up.
因此我的等级越来越高
Eventually, I gave up, buried my feelings…
最终我放弃了 埋藏了我的感情
And decided to simply fulfill my role.
决定简单地履行我的职责
You know, you talk like you don't care
你知道吗？ 你说话的语气好像毫不在乎
about your duty or your house.
你的责任和你的家族
Ah, n… no!
不 不是的
You can't hide it. It's obvious, tanuki boy!
你掩饰不了 这很明显 狸猫小子
Then I met her…
然后我遇见了她
Her eyes that could see right through me,
她那双能看穿我内心的眼睛
and her many cold and brutal deeds bewildered me.
和她的许多冷酷而残忍的行为 使我困惑不已
And so… I don't know why,
所以我不知道为什么
but I, who'd been lying to myself this whole time,
我这个一直在自欺欺人的人
met her, who could only lie to others…
遇到了只对别人撒谎的她
She was so free and bright…
她是如此自由和明亮
I get so jealous I want to cry.
我嫉妒得想哭
She must have used ninja arts on me.
她一定对我使用了忍术
What kind of Asaemon admires a criminal?
一个处刑官怎么会崇拜一个罪犯呢？
No…
不
I think…
我想…
I can understand your feelings a little…
我能稍稍理解你的感受
Just a little.
就一点
Why don't the two of us find a way
为什么我们两个不想一个办法
to help everyone that came to the island?
来帮助每个来到这个岛上的人呢？
Sagiri…
佐切
Okay!
好
I managed to sense Tao…
我成功感应到了道
But I don't think I can use it well.
但我不觉得我能用得很好
And also…
而且
We can't learn anything about the elixir if you kill them.
如果你杀了他们 我们就无法知道不死药的信息了
Ah.
啊
Well, I'd guess from the conversation
我想根据对话推测
that she knows the answer.
她知道答案
It would be cruel to ask her to take us to it,
考虑到怪物们对她的打算
considering what the monsters wanted to do with her.
要求她带我们去找不死药会很残忍
But you were the one who came after me.
但是你是冲着我来的
Right?
对吧？
What was your goal?
你的目标是什么？
If you have something to ask me, ask.
如果你有什么问题就问吧
I owe you for saving me twice.
我欠你两次救命之恩
Sagi wrote in her report…
佐切在报告中写道
This man… is not a heartless person.
这个人并非冷血
However, he only reveals his heart…
然而 他只在
when the situation pertains to a certain person.
涉及特定的人时才表露出内心
"Any other situation would be unusual."
“其他情况都是不寻常的”
Or so she wrote… But, my impression
她是这样写的 但我的印象
is drastically different.
大不相同
That softness…
那种柔软…
What does it mean in this position?
在这种位置上意味着什么？
Hey!
喂！
What…?
这是什么…
Hey…
喂
Were there this many flowers blooming before?
这里之前就开了这么多花吗？
Yuzuriha!
杠！
She's indiscreet…
她太鲁莽了
Cruel…
残忍
A murderer girl drowning in sin…
一个沉溺于罪恶的杀人少女
A strong wind that blew away all of my common sense.
一阵吹散我所有常识的强风
I can't get close.
我不能靠近
I don't have to.
也不需要
If I could only…
如果我能只是
continue watching her from the sidelines…
继续在一旁观察她
Wait… Was I supposed to be painting now?
等等 我现在应该画画吗？
I feel like I was in the middle of doing something else…
我觉得我好像正在做别的事情
Oh well! I'm going to paint another one!
算了 我要再画一幅
Oh… well…
好
I… gon… ain…
我要再…
Kill?
杀人？
Kill!
杀人！
Yuzuriha…
杠
Wh… What should we…?
我…我们该…
Are we going…
我们要再次
to fight this monster again?
跟这个怪物战斗吗？
No… I don't think it's possible now…
不 我觉得现在不可能了
Subtitle translation by: Dale Angles
字幕翻译：朱未耒